<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>TIL on ~stesie's musings</title><link>https://stefansiegl.de/categories/til/</link><description>Recent content in TIL on ~stesie's musings</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.123.7</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2025 Stefan Siegl · all content is CC-BY-SA · Terms of Service</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stefansiegl.de/categories/til/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scripting IntelliJ</title><link>https://stefansiegl.de/2025/03/scripting-intellij/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefansiegl.de/2025/03/scripting-intellij/</guid><description>Recently I learned, that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to script IntelliJ. I picked up on it while Writing an IntelliJ Plugin for my Coverage Tracker project, aka &amp;ldquo;Undercovered&amp;rdquo;. So there is the IDE scripting console, which comes out-of-the-box. You just open the Action panel and search for IDE Scripting Console, next a tiny popup menu should show, asking for whether it should be Groovy or Kotlin (beta). Right away you can enter some code and evaluate it by pressing Control + Return.</description></item><item><title>Chromium Site Search</title><link>https://stefansiegl.de/2025/02/chromium-site-search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefansiegl.de/2025/02/chromium-site-search/</guid><description>Pretty likely this is a well-known thing to many 🥱, and to be honest, I also kindof knew that Chromium has some search shortcuts, but I never bothered to learn how to use them. To even add to that, I&amp;rsquo;m even well aware that I quite regularly went to pages like dict.leo.org, and used the search feature there. Or I went to our Jira instance, and used the search feature there, regularly just typing a ticket number.</description></item><item><title>JUnit Parameter Resolvers</title><link>https://stefansiegl.de/2024/12/junit-parameter-resolvers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefansiegl.de/2024/12/junit-parameter-resolvers/</guid><description>Today (err, recently) I learned &amp;hellip; that JUnit&amp;rsquo;s extension API allows for parameter resolvers. These kick in every time you use arguments on a test method, lifecycle method or class constructor. For me, so far, none of these methods ever took an argument. But turns out, it&amp;rsquo;s possible &amp;hellip; and even useful.
They have a primitive example here where they allow a test method to take a random number like so:</description></item><item><title>JUnit Assumptions API</title><link>https://stefansiegl.de/2024/08/junit-assumptions-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefansiegl.de/2024/08/junit-assumptions-api/</guid><description>Today, I discovered a powerful feature in JUnit: the Assumptions API. This API allows you to define assumptions for your tests. If an assumption isn&amp;rsquo;t met, the test execution is aborted rather than marked as failed. This distinction is crucial in scenarios like conditional test execution in CI pipelines. When a test is skipped due to an unmet assumption, it appears as &amp;ldquo;skipped&amp;rdquo; in the test reports, not as &amp;ldquo;passed&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;failed.</description></item></channel></rss>